<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PocketPC on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/pocketpc/</link><description>Recent content in PocketPC on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 10:27:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/pocketpc/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Handheld Linux</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/handheld-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 10:27:05 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/handheld-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have replaced the disk in my Libretto CT100 with a 20GB disk I had going
spare and re-installed Debian Sarge 3.1, this time I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother with the
2.6 kernel or Xfce because I&amp;rsquo;ve had my fun with those now. But playing
around with Linux on my Libretto has re-kindled my interested in running Linux
on small portable devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Earlier this year I experimented with &lt;a href="http://familiar.handhelds.org/">Familiar Linux&lt;/a>
0.8.2 on my iPAQ 3970 and installed via a serial cable, which was very slow
going. So I&amp;rsquo;ve invested in a 512MB Compact Flash card to speed up my next
round of tinkering with Familiar but this time I intend to leave Familiar
installed and not re-flash the 3970 with PocketPC 2002. The
&lt;a href="http://familiar.handhelds.org/releases/v0.8.2/install/index.html">Familiar v0.8.2 Installation&lt;/a>
guide covers pretty much everything you need to know about the installation
process.&lt;/p></description><summary>Craving a handheld Linux device</summary></item><item><title>Pocket Entertainment</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/pocket-entertainment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2005 09:36:08 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/pocket-entertainment/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently discovered &lt;a href="http://www.scummvm.org/">ScummVM&lt;/a> and have started playing
&lt;em>Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders&lt;/em> for the first time in years! ScummVM
allows you to run certain classic graphical point-and-click adventure games,
provided you already have their data files, allowing you to play them on
systems for which they were never designed!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I decided to organise my old adventure games for use with ScummVM so that I
can enjoy them all again, but this has led to a couple of eBay bids to buy some
games I am missing. I have used the ScummVM tools to compress as the game data
files so I can fit the games on my iPAQ 4150. Life is good. I have been thinking
of getting a new solid state Ogg Vorbis compatible portable music player but
haven&amp;rsquo;t found one which completely suits my needs. So, my iPAQ 4150 is now
standing in as my portable music player too. This is thanks too the excellent
GSPlayer. I have configured my iPAQ 4150 to be a full time entertainment device.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am off to get myself a decent set of head phones today, more on that later&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description><summary>Using an iPAQ 4150 PocketPC for games &amp;amp; music</summary></item></channel></rss>