<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Libretto CT100 on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/libretto-ct100/</link><description>Recent content in Libretto CT100 on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 10:27:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/libretto-ct100/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Handheld Linux</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/handheld-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 10:27:05 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/handheld-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have replaced the disk in my Libretto CT100 with a 20GB disk I had going
spare and re-installed Debian Sarge 3.1, this time I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother with the
2.6 kernel or Xfce because I&amp;rsquo;ve had my fun with those now. But playing
around with Linux on my Libretto has re-kindled my interested in running Linux
on small portable devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Earlier this year I experimented with &lt;a href="http://familiar.handhelds.org/">Familiar Linux&lt;/a>
0.8.2 on my iPAQ 3970 and installed via a serial cable, which was very slow
going. So I&amp;rsquo;ve invested in a 512MB Compact Flash card to speed up my next
round of tinkering with Familiar but this time I intend to leave Familiar
installed and not re-flash the 3970 with PocketPC 2002. The
&lt;a href="http://familiar.handhelds.org/releases/v0.8.2/install/index.html">Familiar v0.8.2 Installation&lt;/a>
guide covers pretty much everything you need to know about the installation
process.&lt;/p></description><summary>Craving a handheld Linux device</summary></item><item><title>Debian 3.1 on Libretto CT100</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/debian-3.1-on-libretto-ct100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2005 10:26:14 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/debian-3.1-on-libretto-ct100/</guid><description>&lt;p>I decided to stick with the 2.1GB hard disk in the end, but in order to
complete the initial install I fitted it in an old IBM Thinkpad 600X. This
allowed me to boot off the Debian 3.1 Net Install CD and get a basic system
installed. Once that was done I fitted the hard disk back in the Libretto and
installed the essential bits and pieces I needed. I am feeling a lot of love
for &lt;code>apt-get&lt;/code> today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I got carried away. I upgraded to the 2.6 kernel, installed X and
Xfce 4.2.2. Then I migrated to the testing repositories, the upgrade for which
has finished a few minutes ago. I found Quentin Stafford-Fraser&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href="http://www.qandr.org/quentin/libretto/">Linux on the Libretto 100CT&lt;/a> page very
helpful in finding the right Modeline settings to get X going. I don&amp;rsquo;t really
need Xfce on the Libretto but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist getting it running. Despite the
low spec processor and just 64MB of RAM it runs very well, even Firefox is
usable. I might have to bring this box along to the next HantsLUG meeting.&lt;/p></description><summary>Running Xfce &amp;amp; Firefox on the Toshiba Libretto CT100</summary></item><item><title>Server crash! But I have the perfect replacement</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/server-crash-but-i-have-the-perfect-replacement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2005 10:18:22 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/server-crash-but-i-have-the-perfect-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>The CPU fan on my home server stopped spinning, which has rendered the computer
unusable until I find the time to replace it. I have my workstation, so I can
keep working for the most part, but the services I was running on the server
are critical so I need a server replacement ASAP. I have decided to setup a
dedicated server for those services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always knew my Libretto CT100 would come in handy someday. With 64MB RAM
and a Pentium 166mhz MMX CPU I think it will make an excellent server. Although
I may upgrade the hard disk from 2.1GB to 20GB. I am undecided which distro I&amp;rsquo;ll
install, probably Ubuntu 5.10 or Debian 3.1, but because the Libretto CT100
has weird hardware this install is not straight forward. The following web pages
seem to be the most useful to me right now:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.geocities.com/davissharonforest/">Installing Debian Linux 3.1 Sarge on Toshiba Libretto 50&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.redgrittybrick.org/linux/libretto.html">Installing RedHat Linux on a Toshiba Libretto 100CT&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Has good background information on the hardware and hibernation partition&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>There are several other installs documented on the &lt;a href="http://www.linux-on-laptops.com/toshiba.html">Linux on Toshiba Laptop and Notebook Computers&lt;/a> page.&lt;/p></description><summary>Running a Linux server on a Libretto CT100</summary></item></channel></rss>