<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R3-born on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/r3-born/</link><description>Recent content in R3-born on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 21:59:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/r3-born/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>R3-born 0.1.1 is released!</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/r3-born-0.1.1-is-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 21:59:45 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/r3-born-0.1.1-is-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/r3-born/">R3-born&lt;/a> 0.1.1 is released :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="r3-born-core-change-log">R3-born Core Change Log&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here are the main changes for this release. &lt;em>v0.1.1 : 9th March 2007&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Akismet anti-spam API&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added a version checker for the Core and also for Blocks and Modules.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added search bot (Google, MSN, Yahoo!, etc) detection.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added logging (in Combined Log Format) to the R3-born Intrusion Prevention System.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enhanced the Module API so it now supports safe updating and custom CSS for blocks and modules.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enhanced the Layout Manager&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enhanced the Registration and Profile pages by separating them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enhanced the Template engine by back porting some features from phpBB 3.0.x&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimised and fixed the Search API&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimised and simplified Coloured Groups.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improved the Groups Management ACP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improved the Styles Management ACP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed various bugs in the core.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Significant feature enhancements, bug fixes and optimisations added to the Menu and Who Is Online blocks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Significant feature enhancements, bug fixes and optimisations added to the Comments, Downloads, Forum, Pages,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Private Messages, Weblogs and View Online modules.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New modules : bot_list, cookie, error, google, referrers and sql_backup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New blocks : recent_blogs, recent_comments, recent_pages, recent_topics, search, socmarks and visit_counter.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>R3-born 0.1.1 has fulfilled its first major objective, which is to be functional
enough to run a website.&lt;/p></description><summary>R3-born is good enough to run a website</summary></item><item><title>R3-born 0.1.0 is released!</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/r3-born-0.1.0-is-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 11:52:55 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/r3-born-0.1.0-is-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finally, R3-born 0.1.0 is released. &lt;a href="http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/r3-born/">R3-born&lt;/a>
is a content management system for modest websites which I hope will be ideal for
individuals running their own sites or small community websites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to my accident I have not been able to address all of the bugs which have
been reported recently and the downloads are only available as bzip2 tarballs
right now. Please report any bugs you might encounter as 0.1.0 has really only
been tested on Debian Sarge (stable) running PHP4 and MSQL 4. Feedback from
other configurations will be useful and all reported bugs will be investigated.&lt;/p></description><summary>After 10 months work R3-born 0.1.0 is ready</summary></item><item><title>Announcing R3-born</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/announcing-r3-born/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2006 17:48:47 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/announcing-r3-born/</guid><description>&lt;p>I suppose it is a bit silly to announce this just before I go on holiday but
what the heck. &lt;a href="http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/r3-born/">R3-born&lt;/a> is
intended to be a simple and modular content management system for modest websites.
My hope is that it will be ideal for individuals running their own sites or for
small community websites. R3-born is coded in PHP (4.2.0 or better required)
and requires an SQL database, currently MySQL 3.x, 4.x and 5.x, Postgres 7.x
or better and MS-SQL 7.x or better are supported.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="current-status">Current Status&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Right now, R3-born is considered pre-alpha and not suitable for a production
website but is ready for testers to start feeding back on bugs, feature requests
and in the near future code changes. Development has been fairly rapid so far. I
started the project in April 2006 and I hope to release a beta version of
R3-born later in 2006.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/r3-born/">http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/r3-born/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Minerva is r3-born</summary></item><item><title>Comments off, Overdue update and R3-born</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/comments-off-overdue-update-and-r3-born/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2006 13:14:55 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/comments-off-overdue-update-and-r3-born/</guid><description>&lt;p>First of all, I have disabled comments on my blog. &lt;a href="http://jaws-project.com/">Jaws&lt;/a>
has spam protection and captachs but both implementations suck. This site doesn&amp;rsquo;t
generate much feedback so disabling comments altogether is not really a problem.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t updated the site recently and here is why. The 0.6.x release of Jaws
is buggy and I still haven&amp;rsquo;t found anything else which fully meets my needs for
managing my own web content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Therefore for the last couple of months I have been working on an open source
CMS of my own called R3-born. More details to follow about that soon, but you
can find the project over at Sourceforge, don&amp;rsquo;t expect anything to work
(although it does for the most part) it is pre-alpha and unreleased. SVN is the
only way to snag the source.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/r3-born/">R3-born&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Jaws spam counter measures suck</summary></item></channel></rss>