<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minerva on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/minerva/</link><description>Recent content in Minerva on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 17:42:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/minerva/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project Minerva is coming home</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/project-minerva-is-coming-home/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 17:42:11 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/project-minerva-is-coming-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>Despite a generous offer from a Minerva enthusiast a year or so ago to freely
host the Project Minerva sites, all the Project Minerva hosting is coming back
to where it started and rightly belongs. Yes, right here with me. It just
goes to show you really don&amp;rsquo;t get anything for free. The developers have had
several outages with the server which was provided by SpiderTech Hosting, so
we are bringing it back here where we can look after our interests directly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Minerva users might be wondering if the fact I am fully hosting Project
Minerva again means I am going to be developing for the project again. Well,
we will just have to see but I did inform Chris of a little project I kicked
off last week which may (or may not) lead to something.&lt;/p></description><summary>It&amp;rsquo;s coming home. Minerva is coming home.</summary></item><item><title>Leaving Minerva</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/leaving-minerva/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 09:47:16 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/leaving-minerva/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday was a sad day. I finally notified the core &lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/minerva/">Minerva&lt;/a>
developers that I am leaving the project. Given that I started the project a few
years back it was not a decision I made lightly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a couple of reasons for leaving the project, the main one being that I
just do not have the time available to effectively lead or contribute to the
project. All open source projects require good leadership and I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able
to provide that for most of 2005. It is with the best interests of Minerva in
mind that I decided to leave.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, Minerva is in very good hands and is under active development,
with Dave and Chris leading the effort. I wish all the Minerva developers and
users every success with the upcoming release of R4, it is a marvelous
achievement and I am sure will prove to be very successful. I will be
keeping an eye on R4 development, and if time permits, I may contribute some
blocks and modules in the future. Until then, good luck and make me proud!&lt;/p></description><summary>Standing down from the Minerva project</summary></item></channel></rss>