<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Travel on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/travel/</link><description>Recent content in Travel on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 10:31:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/travel/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Isles of Scilly</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/isles-of-scilly/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 10:31:09 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/isles-of-scilly/</guid><description>&lt;p>I arranged a surprise holiday to the &lt;a href="http://www.scillyonline.co.uk/index.php">Isles of Scilly&lt;/a>
for my wifes birthday and we got back a couple of days ago. What a fantastic place!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We very much enjoyed our short time on the islands and will definately be going
back in the future, I think our enjoyment was also heightened by the fantastic
weather we had during our stay. One of the highlights of the trip was the &lt;a href="http://www.islesofscillyhelicopter.com/">helicopter
flights&lt;/a> to and from the islands,
which gives you some great views of the Cornish coast line and &lt;a href="http://www.landsend-landmark.co.uk/">Lands
End&lt;/a>. The Scilly Isles have a rich history
and this is slowly revealed as you visit each island and the attractions they
offer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The scenery is beautiful everywhere, but the &lt;a href="http://www.tresco.co.uk/the_abbey_garden/default.asp">Abbey Garden&lt;/a>
on &lt;a href="http://www.tresco.co.uk/">Tresco&lt;/a> is very impressive. A side from island
hoping and wandering around the island coastal pathways we also went out to see
some grey seals out on the rocks to the west of the islands. Other highlights
are the plentiful supply of &lt;em>real&lt;/em> &lt;a href="http://www.cornishlight.co.uk/cornish-pasty.htm">Cornish pasties&lt;/a>,
cream teas and ice cream. The food on the islands was very good and if you like
fish you are in for a treat. The views of the sunsets are lovely and best
accompanied with a pint of ale &lt;code>:-)&lt;/code>&lt;/p></description><summary>A surprise holiday in the Isles of Scilly</summary></item></channel></rss>