<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MP3 on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/mp3/</link><description>Recent content in MP3 on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 22:30:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/mp3/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Amazon Loves Linux Music Lovers</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/amazon-loves-linux-music-lovers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 22:30:48 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/amazon-loves-linux-music-lovers/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve no idea when Amazon.co.uk launched their MP3 store and I&amp;rsquo;ve no idea when
they released their Linux client for downloading the MP3s you purchased. I
don&amp;rsquo;t care, I just want to say I&amp;rsquo;m really impressed Amazon have considered us
Linux users. Well done Amazon!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not only that but the MP3s are DRM free, encoded using variable bit rates aiming
at an average of 256 kilobits per second (kbps), album cover art is included with
each song and the tracks are typically cheaper than iTunes. Well done again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Doubtless some would want an Open Source client and unencumbered formats such as
Ogg and FLAC, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with what Amazon have on offer so long as it
works. Which it does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, the Linux MP3 downloader client is 32-bit only. Not so good, but
it can be successfully installed in 64-bit Ubuntu. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did in on
Ubuntu Jaunty 9.04 64-bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>wget -c http://frozenfox.freehostia.com/cappy/getlibs-all.deb
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>dpkg -i getlibs-all.deb    
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>wget &lt;span style="color:#87ceeb">&amp;#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/dmusic/help/amd-installer-redirect.html/ref=dm_amd_linux_ubuntu?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;forceos=LINUX&amp;amp;callingPage=%2Fgp%2Fdmusic%2Fhelp%2Famd.html&amp;amp;linux_Ubuntu.x=1&amp;#34;&lt;/span> -O amazonmp3.deb
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>dpkg -i --force-architecture amazonmp3.deb
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>getlibs /usr/bin/amazonmp3
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description><summary>Amazon treats Linux users like 1st class citizens</summary></item><item><title>MP3Gainer - Apply ReplayGain to your entire music library</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mp3gainer-apply-replaygain-to-your-entire-music-library/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 15:25:45 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mp3gainer-apply-replaygain-to-your-entire-music-library/</guid><description>&lt;p>Work has been crazy. We&amp;rsquo;re moving house. Hence, not much time for geeky stuff
recently. I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting this off for ages, I need to &amp;ldquo;normalise&amp;rdquo; the
volume of my MP3 music music library. Not all CDs sound equally loud. Whilst
different musical moods require that some tracks should sound louder than
others, the loudness of a given CD has more to do with the year of issue or
the whim of the producer than the intended emotional effect. This difference
carries over when you rip the CD to MP3 and random play through my music
collection requires constant manual volume adjustment. This has been bugging
me for a while now, but when it started to bug my wife I knew it was time to
find a solution. My main concerns with applying some sort of audio
normalisation were&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>My MP3s should not be irretrievably changed into something I end up hating.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The method used should be free of the application used for music playback,
given that I play my music on iPod Nano, iPod Shuffle, PSP, PS3, Linux desktops,
TomTom 720T FM streaming and in car MP3 player.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After some research &lt;a href="http://mp3gain.sourceforge.net">mp3gain&lt;/a> seems to be the
tool for the job which provides an implementation of
&lt;a href="http://www.replaygain.org/">ReplayGain&lt;/a>. However, as of today my entire CD
collection is ripped, which is very large, so I needed a way to process my
whole music collection in an automated fashion. I found some examples of how
to script this, but there are caveats with the solutions I found. Therefore I
have created my own script, MP3Gainer, to apply ReplayGain using &lt;code>mp3gain&lt;/code>
which overcomes these common limitations. MP3Gainer recursively applies
ReplayGain to a MP3 music collection of any size and directory depth.
ReplayGain can be applied in &amp;rsquo;track&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;album&amp;rsquo; mode and if ReplayGain has
previously been applied it can also be undone. It is important to understand
that MP3Gainer &amp;lsquo;album&amp;rsquo; mode really is per album, which is what you want. Trust
me! This script works on Ubuntu, should work on any other Linux/Unix
flavour and possibly Mac OS X providing you have the required tools installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/MP3Gainer">MP3Gainer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Volume normalise an entire MP3 library the right way</summary></item><item><title>Mediatomb 0.12 - Streaming audio and video around the house</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mediatomb-0.12-streaming-audio-and-video-around-the-house/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 16:23:39 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mediatomb-0.12-streaming-audio-and-video-around-the-house/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://mediatomb.cc/">Mediatomb&lt;/a> is an open source (GPL) UPnP MediaServer
with a nice web user interface, it allows you to stream your digital media
through your home network and listen to/watch it on a variety of UPnP
compatible devices, such as the PlayStation in my case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mediatomb 0.12 is not yet released as final yet but it is certainly stable
enough for general use, so I spent the last week migrating from Mediatomb 0.11
to Mediatomb 0.12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently finished ripping my entire CD collection (344 CDs) to MP3 and I
am currently ripping my DVD collection (85 done so far) to MP4 with AAC 5.1
audio. The &amp;lsquo;Music&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Video&amp;rsquo; folders in our home directories are mounted via
NFS. The Mediatomb server uses the same data sources so any playlists or new
music/videos we might import are immediately reflected in Mediatomb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our entire CD library is now available at the click of a button, automatically
organised by genre, artist and date. We have also created some playlists
in &lt;code>.m3u&lt;/code> or &lt;code>.pls&lt;/code> format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New to Mediatomb 0.12 is the ability to scrobble your music to
&lt;a href="http://www.last.fm">Last.fm&lt;/a>, this a killer feature for me and why I chose to
migrate to 0.12 before it goes final.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ripped the CDs using &lt;a href="http://www.burtonini.com/blog/computers/sound-juicer">SoundJuicer&lt;/a>,
since I can configure it to use &lt;a href="http://lame.cvs.sourceforge.net/viewvc/lame/lame/doc/html/presets.html">LAME presets&lt;/a>.
I then used the &lt;a href="http://musicbrainz.org/doc/PicardTagger">Music Brainz Picard Tagger&lt;/a> to
add additional tagging and embed cover art and then applied ReplayGain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally my wife and I use &lt;a href="http://banshee-project.org/">Banshee&lt;/a> to manage the
music library on our computers, including the creation of playlists and syncing
to our iPods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am using &lt;a href="http://handbrake.fr/">Handbrake&lt;/a> to rip the DVDs to MP4. I&amp;rsquo;ve created a
new PS3 compatible profile which is focused on quality, I&amp;rsquo;ll post details
about that in the future. Mediatomb 0.12 has some experimental features to
stream video content from .ISO images of DVDs. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to play with that but
it sounds very cool. I&amp;rsquo;ve also created a script which queries IMDB to
categorise our film library by genre and create summary information about
each film in the library. I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting more about that soon. I haven&amp;rsquo;t
finalised how we will integrate Photo management with Mediatomb yet, but that
is that final piece in the puzzle.&lt;/p></description><summary>In home streaming via UPnP with Mediatomb</summary></item><item><title>Cheap and Cheerful MP3 Player</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/cheap-and-cheerful-mp3-player/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2006 13:00:10 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/cheap-and-cheerful-mp3-player/</guid><description>&lt;p>My six year old MP3 player just isn&amp;rsquo;t up to the job anymore and I have been
looking for an alternative, on and off, over that last few weeks. Ideally I
would have liked a portable music player that supported Ogg Vorbis but as my
home cinema isn&amp;rsquo;t Ogg Vorbis compatible I decided to standardize on MP3. No
flames please!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have lots of MMC and SD memory cards that I have collected over the years so
decided get a player which could make use of them. I only need a player for use
in the gym and while cycling so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be too fancy, with that in
mind I decided to get the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Sumvision-Snowfox-XT105-Portable-Playback/dp/B000F9TD1S">Sumvision XT105 MP3 Player&lt;/a>
which is super cheap and surprisingly good considering the price &lt;code>:-)&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Initial impressions are that the manual was obviously translated from Chinese to
English using Google, the included headphones are not much cop. That said,
once you plug-in a decent set of head phones the sound reproduction is very good
and more than good enough for what I want it for and although playlists aren&amp;rsquo;t
supported playback by folder is. That player is very light and very small, so
ideal for use in the gym and battery life is around 10-12 hours from a single
AAA battery. It is also Linux compatible, although I have been using a USB
card reader to populate my memory cards with MP3s as the XT105 is only USB 1.1
and therefore a bit slow. I am off to the gym now with some banging tunes.&lt;/p></description><summary>Cheap as chips MP3 player upgrade</summary></item><item><title>Pocket Entertainment</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/pocket-entertainment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2005 09:36:08 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/pocket-entertainment/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently discovered &lt;a href="http://www.scummvm.org/">ScummVM&lt;/a> and have started playing
&lt;em>Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders&lt;/em> for the first time in years! ScummVM
allows you to run certain classic graphical point-and-click adventure games,
provided you already have their data files, allowing you to play them on
systems for which they were never designed!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I decided to organise my old adventure games for use with ScummVM so that I
can enjoy them all again, but this has led to a couple of eBay bids to buy some
games I am missing. I have used the ScummVM tools to compress as the game data
files so I can fit the games on my iPAQ 4150. Life is good. I have been thinking
of getting a new solid state Ogg Vorbis compatible portable music player but
haven&amp;rsquo;t found one which completely suits my needs. So, my iPAQ 4150 is now
standing in as my portable music player too. This is thanks too the excellent
GSPlayer. I have configured my iPAQ 4150 to be a full time entertainment device.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am off to get myself a decent set of head phones today, more on that later&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description><summary>Using an iPAQ 4150 PocketPC for games &amp;amp; music</summary></item></channel></rss>