<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/windows/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quickemu</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/projects/quickemu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/projects/quickemu/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quickly create and run highly optimised desktop virtual machines for Linux,
macOS and Windows; with just two commands. You decide what operating system you
want to run and &lt;a href="https://github.com/quickemu-project/quickemu">Quickemu&lt;/a> will figure out the best way to do it for you&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Organisation: &lt;a href="https://github.com/quickemu-project">Quickemu Project&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Date: March 2020 - date&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Role: Project Lead&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Quickly create and run optimised Windows, macOS and Linux virtual machines</summary></item><item><title>Distributing closed source Python applications</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/distributing-closed-source-python-applications/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 13:04:03 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/distributing-closed-source-python-applications/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last November we switched to &lt;a href="http://www.python.org/">Python&lt;/a> as the principal
language for all new software development projects at work, ditching Microsoft
Visual C++ and PHP in the process. Last Friday we released our first Python
application to our customers for both Windows and Linux users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although we make good use of Open Source software development tools and
methodologies the application we have just written is propritary and the
source can not be released publicly. We needed to compile, or &lt;em>freeze&lt;/em>, the
Python script in order to create a standalone executable. Tools that do this
have been around for sometime, however our application makes use of Win32
Extensions for Python and WMI on Windows, DBUS/HAL on Linux, wxPython
on both, and a number of other modules. This is quite a big ask for the Python
script compilers and initially the only tool which could build this lot
successfully was &lt;a href="http://www.py2exe.org/">py2exe&lt;/a>. Sadly that only solves part
of the problem since it is a Windows only tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we found &lt;a href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/bbfreeze/">bbfreeze&lt;/a>, which
supports both Windows and Linux with Mac OS X support being actively
developed. &lt;code>bbfreeze&lt;/code> has a simple build API and we were soon using it to build
stand alone executables for both Windows and Linux. Everything is peachy, all
we needed was as means to install our application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We only need a tarball for Linux since we manage all kiosk installations, but
our customer can install the Windows version. Enter &lt;a href="http://www.jrsoftware.org/isinfo.php">InnoSetup&lt;/a>.
InnoSetup is a free installer for Windows programs and installer can even be
created from the command line, perfect for integration with our Jenkins build
servers.&lt;/p></description><summary>Freezing proprietary Python applications for distribution to clients</summary></item><item><title>Portable app</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/portable-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2006 05:40:07 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/portable-app/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started a new job last week, I am contracting for the first time. I needed
some applications installed on my desktop at work, but to do so would not be
permitted as part of my clients standard build policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I started making a USB disk with the tools I needed and in doing do I found
the &lt;a href="http://portableapps.com/">Portableapp&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.portablefreeware.com/">The Portable Freeware Collection&lt;/a>
websites which ease the process no end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A portable app is a computer program that you can carry around with you on a
portable device and use on any Windows computer. When your USB thumb drive,
portable hard drive, iPod or other portable device is plugged in, you have
access to your software and personal data just as you would on your own PC. And
when you unplug, none of your personal data is left behind.&lt;/p></description><summary>Working around corporate Windows policies with Portable Apps</summary></item><item><title>Slimlining Windows XP with nLite and XPLite</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/slimlining-windows-xp-with-nlite-and-xplite/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2006 06:41:38 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/slimlining-windows-xp-with-nlite-and-xplite/</guid><description>&lt;p>A shocking truth is that despite my preference for Linux I do still have to
use Microsoft Windows/ I have recently started a new job where I am now
required to use Windows XP on my desktop at work and I also need a Windows
computer at home in order to update firmware/software and configure most
devices in my home cinema.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I have decided to install Windows XP on my most aging of laptops so it is
always available for my home cinema tweaking, this also means I can remove dual
boot Windows partitions on my main computer. However, because my old laptop is a
bit short on memory I need to tweak Windows XP a good deal. I have been a long
time user of 98Lite and XPLite from &lt;a href="http://www.litepc.com">LitePC.om&lt;/a> and have
been slim lining Windows for many years. I have recently found &lt;a href="http://www.nliteos.com">nLite&lt;/a>
which does much the same as XPLite except it rebuilds the Windows XP (or Windows 2000 and
Windows 2003) installation CD so that the configuration changes you make, and
Windows components you remove, are ingrained in a new ISO image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biggest benefit is that using nLite I can integrate Service Pack 2 and all
the current hotfixes and patches into the new ISO meaning that after an install
the new Windows system is better secured. I have also been able to integrate Firefox
into my custom Windows XP install CD and completely remove Internet Explorer,
and by using the &lt;a href="http://windowsupdate.62nds.com/">WindizUpdate&lt;/a> it is possible
to do online Windows Updates using Firefox, Opera and K-Meleon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are also many other benefits to using nLite other than simply removing or
adding software components, you can also pre-configure just about every aspect
of the Windows environment and nLite will wrap all this into an unattended
installation ISO image. My custom Windows XP install CD I made with nLite is
just 145mb!&lt;/p></description><summary>Trimming the Windows fat with nLite</summary></item></channel></rss>