<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thunderbird on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/thunderbird/</link><description>Recent content in Thunderbird on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 15:41:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/thunderbird/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zindus contact sync for Thunderbird and Zimbra</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/zindus-contact-sync-for-thunderbird-and-zimbra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 15:41:24 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/zindus-contact-sync-for-thunderbird-and-zimbra/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I setup the mail server at work I picked &lt;a href="http://www.zimbra.com/">Zimbra&lt;/a>.
It&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today Zimbra just got a bit better when I found &lt;a href="http://www.zindus.com">Zindus&lt;/a>.
Zindus is open source software and runs on all Thunderbird platforms including
Windows, Mac OSX and Linux. Zindus can sync your contacts between Zimbra and
Thunderbird. It syncs everything from Address Books to your GAL (Global Address List).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It currently supports ZCS 3.x to 5.x. Adding the &lt;a href="http://www.mozilla.org/projects/calendar/">Lightning&lt;/a>
and Zindus add-ons to Thunderbird create a very complete desktop client to
Zimbra for any platform. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to share to good news with my Outlook users.&lt;/p></description><summary>Zimbra contact syncing for Thunderbird on Linux</summary></item><item><title>Simple iCal Server</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/simple-ical-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 23:20:28 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/simple-ical-server/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the longest time I have been meaning to setup a shared calendar for my
wife I and to use. You see, like most men I have no idea when and where I am
supposed to be. This is because my wife keeps all this information in her
filofax and that lives in her handbag, somewhere I never venture. So I have
spent this evening setting up &lt;a href="http://phpicalendar.net/">PHP iCalendar&lt;/a> on
&lt;a href="http://www.lighttpd.net/">Lighttpd&lt;/a>, and I am very happy with the results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have opted to use the &lt;code>publish.php&lt;/code> add-on provided with PHP iCalendar, rather
than add the WebDAV module to Lighty. For our modest requirements it works
very well. We now have full read/write access to our calendar by using the
&lt;a href="http://www.mozilla.org/projects/calendar/">Lightning&lt;/a> extension for
Thunderbird and read only access via the PHP iCalendar web interface. Viewing
the calendar via the web interface requires a login first and the calendar
publishing is protected by Lighty authentication using htdigest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lastly, because our calendar is a nice open standard I have options as to how I
might sync it with my mobile phone. More on that when I figure it out.&lt;/p></description><summary>Creating a self-hosted shared calendar</summary></item></channel></rss>