<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>98Lite on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/98lite/</link><description>Recent content in 98Lite on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2006 06:41:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/98lite/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slimlining Windows XP with nLite and XPLite</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/slimlining-windows-xp-with-nlite-and-xplite/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2006 06:41:38 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/slimlining-windows-xp-with-nlite-and-xplite/</guid><description>&lt;p>A shocking truth is that despite my preference for Linux I do still have to
use Microsoft Windows/ I have recently started a new job where I am now
required to use Windows XP on my desktop at work and I also need a Windows
computer at home in order to update firmware/software and configure most
devices in my home cinema.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I have decided to install Windows XP on my most aging of laptops so it is
always available for my home cinema tweaking, this also means I can remove dual
boot Windows partitions on my main computer. However, because my old laptop is a
bit short on memory I need to tweak Windows XP a good deal. I have been a long
time user of 98Lite and XPLite from &lt;a href="http://www.litepc.com">LitePC.om&lt;/a> and have
been slim lining Windows for many years. I have recently found &lt;a href="http://www.nliteos.com">nLite&lt;/a>
which does much the same as XPLite except it rebuilds the Windows XP (or Windows 2000 and
Windows 2003) installation CD so that the configuration changes you make, and
Windows components you remove, are ingrained in a new ISO image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biggest benefit is that using nLite I can integrate Service Pack 2 and all
the current hotfixes and patches into the new ISO meaning that after an install
the new Windows system is better secured. I have also been able to integrate Firefox
into my custom Windows XP install CD and completely remove Internet Explorer,
and by using the &lt;a href="http://windowsupdate.62nds.com/">WindizUpdate&lt;/a> it is possible
to do online Windows Updates using Firefox, Opera and K-Meleon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are also many other benefits to using nLite other than simply removing or
adding software components, you can also pre-configure just about every aspect
of the Windows environment and nLite will wrap all this into an unattended
installation ISO image. My custom Windows XP install CD I made with nLite is
just 145mb!&lt;/p></description><summary>Trimming the Windows fat with nLite</summary></item></channel></rss>