<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PlayStation 3 on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/playstation-3/</link><description>Recent content in PlayStation 3 on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 15:34:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/playstation-3/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mediatomb vs. MiniDLNA</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mediatomb-vs-minidlna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 15:34:12 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mediatomb-vs-minidlna/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href="http://mediatomb.cc/">Mediatomb&lt;/a> for nearly two years now but
decided to give &lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/minidlna/">MiniDLNA&lt;/a> a whirl
since it is a fully fledged DLNA server whereas Mediatomb is UPnP only. I&amp;rsquo;m
currently running both Mediatomb SVN and MiniDLNA CVS. So, how does MiniDLNA
compare to Mediatomb?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>MiniDLNA is easier to compile, configure, uses less RAM and has less software
dependencies than Mediatomb.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MiniDLNA doesn&amp;rsquo;t currently support music play lists or Last.fm scrobbling.
Mediatomb supports &lt;code>.m3u&lt;/code> and &lt;code>.pls&lt;/code> playlists but requires a 3rd party patch
to add Last.fm scrobbling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MiniDLNA doesn&amp;rsquo;t support dynamic video thumbnail creation, which would be
nice to have but is not essential, cover images are supported. Mediatomb
supports video thumbnails via &lt;code>ffmpegthumbnailer&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MiniDLNA doesn&amp;rsquo;t currently have any transcoding support. This is of little
consequence for me since I import video content into my library in a format
natively supported by the PS3, either MP3, MPEG-2 TS or MPEG-4. Mediatomb
does support transcoding but it is somewhat fiddly to setup and you can&amp;rsquo;t
pause transcoded content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MiniDLNA works &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;out of the box&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> with the PS3 (and other DLNA clients)
while Mediatomb requires some tweaking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mediatomb&amp;rsquo;s default video import script doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit how I organise my
video library, but MiniDLNA suits my video library perfectly.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>So, as of today I am running both Mediatomb and MiniDLNA. Mediatomb is
exclusively handling audio since playlist and Last.fm support are essential
for me. MiniDLNA is now handling video exclusively. I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with the
results but should MiniDLNA add .m3u/.pls play lists and Last.fm support I
will switch everything to MiniDLNA.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-years-later">2 years later&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since writing this post MiniDLNA added support for playlists. It still doesn&amp;rsquo;t
support Last.fm scrobbling though. Despite that I switched to MiniDLNA and it
has been streaming audio and video around the house for that last couple of
years.&lt;/p></description><summary>Comparing Mediatomb and MiniDLNA streaming servers</summary></item><item><title>DVD to MPEG2-TS Ripper for Linux</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ts-ripper-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 07:53:58 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ts-ripper-for-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>A while back I released a script that rips a DVD to MPEG-2 PS allowing the
user to select one audio stream and one subtitle stream. Optionally the video
can be requantised, using M2VRequantiser and an ISO image created. If creating
an ISO image the chapters are also preserved from the original DVD. You can
see the original post below.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="2009-04-dvd-mpeg2ps-ripper-linux.html">DVD to MPEG-2 PS Ripper for Linux&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve just released an update to that original script which fixes subtitles in
the original MPEG-2 PS mode but now adds the capability to rip MPEG-2 TS. The
video stream can still be shrunk and in MPEG-2 PS mode the video is still
requantised but in MPEG-2 TS mode the video is re-encoded as H.264.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Requantising is faster but can introduce artifacting. H.264 encoding is
slower, but produces very good quality. I am currently re-importing my entire
DVD collection, using this script, to my DLNA server using MPEG-2 TS and
re-encoding the video to H.264. This gives me high quality rips at relatively
small size (~3Gb) whilst preserving Dolby Digital 5.1 audio. Perfect for
playback via DLNA on the PS3. Some things to be aware of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Subtitles are only supported in MPEG-2 PS mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MPEG-2 PS files created by this script are DVD compliant.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ISO files created by this script will preserve the chapters from the original DVD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The PS3 can only play DTS audio in MPEG-2 PS streams when they have been authored to DVD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The PS3 can only play subtitles in MPEG-2 PS streams when they have been authored to DVD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The PS3 can&amp;rsquo;t play DTS audio in MPEG-2 TS streams therefore this script will transcode DTS to AC3 when in MPEG-2 TS mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To download the script and find out how to make full use of it visit the
release page below.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/DVD-to-MPG">DVD-to-MPG&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Ripping DVDs to MPEG-2 Transport Streams for DLNA streaming</summary></item><item><title>PS3, Mediatomb, Multi Zone Music streaming</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/ps3-mediatomb-multi-zone-music-streaming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 11:02:52 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/ps3-mediatomb-multi-zone-music-streaming/</guid><description>&lt;p>PlayStation 3 firmware 3.00 added a new feature I was very excited about,
multi-av output. Today I finally got round to re-wiring the home cinema system
to make use of this new feature. I now have the PS3 streaming music from
&lt;a href="http://mediatomb.cc/">MediaTomb&lt;/a> with my A/V receiver sending audio to Zone
1 via digital inter connects and also sending audio to Zone 2 via analog stereo
interconnects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zone 1 is a 5.1 speaker setup and Zone 2 is a 2.0 all weather wireless speaker
system which are often in the kitchen but also moved outside for parties. If
Sony could just add Skype to the PS3 and allow the PSP Remote Play to output
audio to both the PS3 and PSP (rather than just one of them) I would be very
happy indeed.&lt;/p></description><summary>Multi Zone music streaming with the PlayStation 3</summary></item><item><title>MKV to MPEG-4 conversion script</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mkv-to-mpeg-4-conversion-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 20:48:58 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mkv-to-mpeg-4-conversion-script/</guid><description>&lt;p>The PlayStation 3 can&amp;rsquo;t play MKV files. Therefore I&amp;rsquo;ve written a script that
creates a PlayStation 3 or Xbox 360 compatible MPEG-4 from Matroska providing
the video is H.264 and audio is AC3 or DTS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Xbox 360 compatibility requires that audio is forcibly downmixed to stereo
with &lt;code>--stereo&lt;/code>. AAC 5.1 audio will have the correct channel assignments when
transcoding from AC3 5.1 and DTS 5.1. If &lt;code>neroAacEnc&lt;/code> is installed then it is
used in preference to &lt;code>faac&lt;/code> for encoding the AAC audio, as it produces better
quality output. &lt;code>neroAacEnc&lt;/code> is optional.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The script does as little re-encoding as possible, only the audio and
subtitles are re-encoded or converted. The script can detect profile 5.1 H.264
and patch it to 4.1 in under a second. Any subtitles in the Matroska are
preserved. If &lt;code>mp4creator&lt;/code> is used the subtitles are extracted stored in a
seperate file. If &lt;code>MP4Box&lt;/code> is used (default) the subtitles are converted to
GPAC Timed Text and muxed into the resulting MPEG-4. The PlayStation 3 can&amp;rsquo;t
display these subtitles but some software players can.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The script can optionally split the Matroska if it is greater than 4GB to ensure
PlayStation 3, Xbox 360 and FAT32 compatibility. This script works on Ubuntu and
should work on any other Linux/Unix flavour and possibly Mac OS X providing you
have the required tools installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/MKV-to-MP4">MKV-to-MP4&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Creating PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360 compatible MPEG-4 videos</summary></item><item><title>PlayStation 3 compatible MPEG-4 container repacker</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/playstation-3-compatible-mpeg-4-container-repacker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 17:09:11 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/playstation-3-compatible-mpeg-4-container-repacker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some of my mobile phones have been able to record video clips in MPEG-4
format. Sadly some of these clips don&amp;rsquo;t play on the PlayStation 3 and those
that do stutter terribly. I use &lt;a href="http://po-ru.com/projects/iplayer-downloader/">iplayer-dl&lt;/a>
to download content from BBC iPlayer. Sadly the files are in a Quicktime
container and are not playable on the PlayStation 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to address both these issues I created a script which extracts the
audio and video from an existing MPEG-4 or ISO Media Apple QuickTime container
and repacks them in a new MPEG-4 container with optional splitting of the
resulting MPEG-4 to maintain FAT32 compatibility. The new MPEG-4 files play
just fine on my PlayStation 3. This script works on Ubuntu, should work on any
other Linux/Unix flavour and possibly Mac OS X providing you have the required
tools installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/MP4-Packer">MP4-Repacker&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Automatically repack MPEG-4 video files for PlayStation 3 compatibility</summary></item><item><title>MKV to M2TS conversion script</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mkv-to-m2ts-conversion-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mkv-to-m2ts-conversion-script/</guid><description>&lt;p>The PlayStation 3 can&amp;rsquo;t play MKV files. Therefore I&amp;rsquo;ve written a
script that creates a PlayStation 3 compatible M2TS from a MKV,
assuming video is H.264 and audio is AC3 or DTS with as little
re-encoding as possible. Any subtitles in the MKV are preserved
in the M2TS although the PlayStation 3 can&amp;rsquo;t display subtitles in M2TS
containers. Optionally splits the M2TS, if it is greater than 4GB,
to maintain FAT32 compatibility. Unlike other MKV to M2TS solutions,
this script doesn&amp;rsquo;t create any intermediate files during the conversion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The PlayStation 3 can&amp;rsquo;t play DTS audio streams in M2TS containers, therefore
DTS audio is transcoded to AC3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This script works on Ubuntu, should work on any other Linux/Unix flavour and
possibly Mac OS X providing you have the required tools installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/MKV-to-M2TS">MKV-to-M2TS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Convert Matroska file to MPEG2-TS for PlayStation 3 compatibility</summary></item><item><title>DVD to MPEG2-PS Ripper for Linux</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ps-ripper-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 16:50:31 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ps-ripper-for-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every so often I find myself in looking through the ex-rental DVD &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;bargain
bin&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>. Quite often I find something I consider a bargain. However, the
experience of watching an ex-rental DVD is typically ruined by the various
trailers and marketing guff at the start which you can&amp;rsquo;t skip. My wife hates
that stuff, and I love my wife, so I routinely rip the main feature of newly
acquired ex-rental DVD movies so we can avoid that crap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I run a Mediatomb DLNA server and I want to load it with all my DVDs. Ripping
them helps reduce the amount of storage I require. MPEG2-PS files are
compatible with my PlayStation 3 which is the client to my Mediatomb DLNA server.
As a solution to the above I created a script, which can extract the main feature
from a DVD video, allowing the user to select one audio stream and one subtitle
stream. Optionally the video can be requantised, using M2VRequantiser, and an ISO
image created. If creating an ISO image the chapters are also preserved from
the original DVD. I&amp;rsquo;ve lobbed my code into GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/DVD-to-MPG">DVD-to-MPG&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Ripping DVDs to MPEG2-PS for streaming via UPnP</summary></item><item><title>IMDB Film Summary as a MPEG-2 video</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/imdb-film-summary-as-a-mpeg-2-video/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 18:00:07 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/imdb-film-summary-as-a-mpeg-2-video/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>UPDATE! I no longer use or maintain the script below. I suggest the vastly
superior &lt;a href="http://www.bunyipawonga.org/sheetmaker/index.php">Sheet Maker for Linux&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve read my blog before you&amp;rsquo;ll know I run Mediatomb DLNA server with my
PlayStation 3 as the client, You&amp;rsquo;ll also know I am working towards importing my
entire DVD collection into my Mediatomb server. However, my wife wants to know
something about each film in the library without having to dig out the DVD
case from storage. My solution is to include a MPEG-2 video displaying the
film summary in the Mediatomb library for each DVD I have imported so it can
be easily viewed from the PS3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My script is called IMDB-to-MPEG and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got round to uploading it.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/IMDB-to-MPEG">IMDB-to-MPEG&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The scripts takes one parameter as input, a film title. The plotline, year of
release, genres, cast list and running time for that film are gathered from IMDB
and formatted as text. Here is an example.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> The Usual Suspects (1995)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> A boat has been destroyed, criminals are dead, and
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> the key to this mystery lies with the only
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> survivor and his twisted, convoluted story
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> beginning with five career crooks in a seemingly
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> random police lineup. (106 mins)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Starring Stephen Baldwin as Michael McManus,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Gabriel Byrne as Dean Keaton, Benicio Del Toro as
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Fred Fenster, Kevin Pollak as Todd Hockney, and
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Kevin Spacey as Roger &amp;#39;Verbal&amp;#39; Kint.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Genres: Crime, Mystery, Thriller.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Rated 8.7 out of 10 from 227,964 votes.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The text is converted into an image and then encoded into a MPEG-2 video using
the lowest possible bitrate/resolution that is acceptable to read when viewing
on a 42&amp;quot; plasma from my sofa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Directories for each matching genre are created and also one for the IMDB
rating (rounded down). The MPEG-2 is stored in the &amp;lsquo;All&amp;rsquo; folder and then
symlinked to the genres and rating for that film. I then copy my video into
the appropriate directory in &amp;lsquo;All&amp;rsquo;. For example.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> .
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |-- All
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |   `-- The_Usual_Suspects
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |       `-- About_The_Usual_Suspects.mpg
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |-- Genres
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |   |-- Crime
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |   |   `-- The_Usual_Suspects -&amp;gt; ../../All/The_Usual_Suspects
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |   |-- Mystery
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |   |   `-- The_Usual_Suspects -&amp;gt; ../../All/The_Usual_Suspects
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |   `-- Thriller
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |       `-- The_Usual_Suspects -&amp;gt; ../../All/The_Usual_Suspects
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> |-- Ratings
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> `-- 8
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> `-- The_Usual_Suspects -&amp;gt; ../../All/The_Usual_Suspects
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This code was lashed up in a few hours, it ain&amp;rsquo;t pretty but it works for me on
my Ubuntu systems, maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll work for you too.&lt;/p></description><summary>Create film preview information for your UPnP server</summary></item><item><title>Converting Matroska to M2TS for PS3 and Mediatomb</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/converting-matroska-to-m2ts-for-ps3-and-mediatomb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 16:19:24 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/converting-matroska-to-m2ts-for-ps3-and-mediatomb/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been a while since I last posted, mainly due to not having Internet
access at home for a month. Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m online again and I have been tinkering
with various projects the most recent of which is Matroska conversion (again).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="matroska-to-mp4">Matroska to MP4&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For sometime I have been converting Martoska files to MPEG-4 with AAC 5.1 audio
so I can stream them via Mediatomb to my PlayStation 3. The conversion process
works well although there is some overhead in transcoding the audio and the
AAC 5.1 audio is not as good quality as the original AC3 or DTS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested I&amp;rsquo;ve put my code in GitHub, the script automates the
whole process.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/MKV-to-MP4">MPV-to-MP4&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="matroska-to-m2ts">Matroska to M2TS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A little while back I read it was possible to convert those same Matroska file
to M2TS files which, so long as the audio is AC3, so takes much less time to
convert. As the PlayStation 3 can&amp;rsquo;t play DTS audio streams inside a M2TS container
there is still a requirement to transcode DTS to AC3. That said the conversion to
M2TS requires less file I/O than converting to MPEG-4 and is therefore it is
generally a quicker conversion method, typically just 2 or 3 minutes on my
workstation at home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus the audio quality of the AC3 or transcoded DTS is better than that of
transcoded AAC 5.1. I&amp;rsquo;ve created my own script to fully automate the conversion
process. The script has been tested on Ubuntu 8.10 64-bit but there is an
outside chance it will work on Mac OS X if you can get the required tools
installed. Again, you can find my script on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/MKV-to-M2TS">MPV-to-M2TS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Fast conversion of Matroska video to MPEG2-TS</summary></item><item><title>Converting DVB-T to DVD Compliant MPEG-2</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/converting-dvb-t-to-dvd-compliant-mpeg-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 23:46:26 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/converting-dvb-t-to-dvd-compliant-mpeg-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am just about to clean up and convert another batch of programmes I have
recorded from Freeview (DVB-T in the UK) so that I can add them to my
DLNA Server. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share the method I use on Ubuntu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By clean up, I mean edit out any adverts and trim crap from the start and the
end of the recordings. It just so happens that the result of this process is
a DVD compliant MPEG-2 which is suitable for DVD authoring, or in my case,
streaming around the house. This method of conversion should work for any DVB
PVR which allows you to export recordings via USB and, of course,
&lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org/">MythTV&lt;/a> or similar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dvb-ripping">DVB Ripping&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have a PlayTV add-on for the PlayStation 3 which enables me to record Freeview
(DVB-T) broadcasts to the PS3 internal hard disk. I mostly use PlayTV to record
films. To prevent the PlayStation 3 hard disk filling up with films I wanted to
export, edit out any adverts and then serve the edited file from my DLNA server
or author it to DVD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This process does not re-encode the audio or video therefore it is fairly quick
and the output is the same quality as the input.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I am using a PlayStation 3 as PVR and MPEG-2 TS (Transport Stream) file
can be converted to a MPEG-2 PS (Program Stream) file using this process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="export-from-playstation-3">Export from PlayStation 3&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="playtv-to-home-menu">PlayTV to Home Menu&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>First we need to move the recording from the PlayTV Library to the PS3 Home Menu.
Start PlayTV, open the Library, select the recording and choose the Move to Home
Menu option.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="copy-from-home-menu-to-external-usb">Copy from Home Menu to External USB&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Quit PlayTV&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Plug in an external (FAT32 formatted) USB drive to the PS3.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to Video on the PS3 Home Menu and select the recording you moved there earlier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Copy from the Options screen and choose the external USB drive as the target.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="clean-mpeg-2-ts-and-convert-to-mpeg-2-ps">Clean MPEG-2 TS and convert to MPEG-2 PS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Plug the USB drive into your Ubuntu workstation and copy the &lt;code>.m2ts&lt;/code> file to your
hard disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will need to &lt;a href="http://project-x.sourceforge.net/">Project X&lt;/a> to clean the
MPEG-2 TS and convert it to MPEG-2 PS.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>apt-get install project-x
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h2 id="edit-out-the-adverts">Edit out the adverts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Start the Project X GUI and load your &lt;code>.m2ts&lt;/code> file.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>File -&amp;gt; Add&lt;/code> and select your .m2ts file.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now use Project X to add cut points to edit out any adverts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="de-multiplex-the-audio-and-video">De-multiplex the audio and video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you have completed your edits you need to &amp;lsquo;demux&amp;rsquo; the &lt;code>.m2ts&lt;/code> file into two
streams, one holding the audio (.mp2) and one holding the video (.m2v).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;code>Prepare &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code> button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>From the &lt;code>Process Window&lt;/code> select the &lt;code>Action&lt;/code> type &lt;code>to M2P&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the start button and wait for the processing to finish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clock the &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Process Windows&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; and quit Project X.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="re-multiplex-the-audio-and-video">Re-multiplex the audio and video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The reason for the de-mux and then re-musing it to ensure the timecodes are
correct, other the video will not playback correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Install MJPEG tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>apt-get install mjpegtools
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Now we need to re-multiplex the audio and video to create a DVD compliant MPEG-2 PS file.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>mplex -f &lt;span style="color:#f60">8&lt;/span> -o muxed-%d.mpg audio.mp2 video.m2v
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The &lt;code>-f 8&lt;/code> option specifies a dvd-compliant stream that is compatible with dvdauthor.
The &lt;code>-o&lt;/code> option specifies the outfile, you can substitute &lt;code>muxed-%d.mpg&lt;/code> with a
more descriptive name if you like. &lt;code>%d&lt;/code> is expanded to a number if &lt;code>mplex&lt;/code> decides
to split the output to several files, this usually happens when the recording
contains commercials and is nothing to worry about.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="author-dvd">Author DVD&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The MPEG-2 PS file that has been created should be suitable for DVD authoring
using DeVeDe. When adding MPEG-2 PS files created using the method above open
the DeVeDe &lt;code>Advanced options&lt;/code> and select &lt;em>This file is already a DVD/xCD-suitable
MPEG-PS file&lt;/em> in the &lt;code>Misc&lt;/code> menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="references">References&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://project-x.sourceforge.net/">http://project-x.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://ttcut.tritime.de/index.2.html">http://ttcut.tritime.de/index.2.html&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://gopchop.org/index.php">http://gopchop.org/index.php&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://gopchop.sourceforge.net/">http://gopchop.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.rastersoft.com/programas/devede.html">http://www.rastersoft.com/programas/devede.html&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Export PlayTV recorded video from PlayStation 3</summary></item></channel></rss>