<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DVD on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/dvd/</link><description>Recent content in DVD on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 07:53:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/dvd/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DVD to MPEG2-TS Ripper for Linux</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ts-ripper-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 07:53:58 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ts-ripper-for-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>A while back I released a script that rips a DVD to MPEG-2 PS allowing the
user to select one audio stream and one subtitle stream. Optionally the video
can be requantised, using M2VRequantiser and an ISO image created. If creating
an ISO image the chapters are also preserved from the original DVD. You can
see the original post below.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="2009-04-dvd-mpeg2ps-ripper-linux.html">DVD to MPEG-2 PS Ripper for Linux&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve just released an update to that original script which fixes subtitles in
the original MPEG-2 PS mode but now adds the capability to rip MPEG-2 TS. The
video stream can still be shrunk and in MPEG-2 PS mode the video is still
requantised but in MPEG-2 TS mode the video is re-encoded as H.264.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Requantising is faster but can introduce artifacting. H.264 encoding is
slower, but produces very good quality. I am currently re-importing my entire
DVD collection, using this script, to my DLNA server using MPEG-2 TS and
re-encoding the video to H.264. This gives me high quality rips at relatively
small size (~3Gb) whilst preserving Dolby Digital 5.1 audio. Perfect for
playback via DLNA on the PS3. Some things to be aware of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Subtitles are only supported in MPEG-2 PS mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MPEG-2 PS files created by this script are DVD compliant.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ISO files created by this script will preserve the chapters from the original DVD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The PS3 can only play DTS audio in MPEG-2 PS streams when they have been authored to DVD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The PS3 can only play subtitles in MPEG-2 PS streams when they have been authored to DVD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The PS3 can&amp;rsquo;t play DTS audio in MPEG-2 TS streams therefore this script will transcode DTS to AC3 when in MPEG-2 TS mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To download the script and find out how to make full use of it visit the
release page below.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/DVD-to-MPG">DVD-to-MPG&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Ripping DVDs to MPEG-2 Transport Streams for DLNA streaming</summary></item><item><title>DVD to MPEG2-PS Ripper for Linux</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ps-ripper-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 16:50:31 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ps-ripper-for-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every so often I find myself in looking through the ex-rental DVD &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;bargain
bin&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>. Quite often I find something I consider a bargain. However, the
experience of watching an ex-rental DVD is typically ruined by the various
trailers and marketing guff at the start which you can&amp;rsquo;t skip. My wife hates
that stuff, and I love my wife, so I routinely rip the main feature of newly
acquired ex-rental DVD movies so we can avoid that crap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I run a Mediatomb DLNA server and I want to load it with all my DVDs. Ripping
them helps reduce the amount of storage I require. MPEG2-PS files are
compatible with my PlayStation 3 which is the client to my Mediatomb DLNA server.
As a solution to the above I created a script, which can extract the main feature
from a DVD video, allowing the user to select one audio stream and one subtitle
stream. Optionally the video can be requantised, using M2VRequantiser, and an ISO
image created. If creating an ISO image the chapters are also preserved from
the original DVD. I&amp;rsquo;ve lobbed my code into GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/DVD-to-MPG">DVD-to-MPG&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Ripping DVDs to MPEG2-PS for streaming via UPnP</summary></item><item><title>Converting DVB-T to DVD Compliant MPEG-2</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/converting-dvb-t-to-dvd-compliant-mpeg-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 23:46:26 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/converting-dvb-t-to-dvd-compliant-mpeg-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am just about to clean up and convert another batch of programmes I have
recorded from Freeview (DVB-T in the UK) so that I can add them to my
DLNA Server. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share the method I use on Ubuntu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By clean up, I mean edit out any adverts and trim crap from the start and the
end of the recordings. It just so happens that the result of this process is
a DVD compliant MPEG-2 which is suitable for DVD authoring, or in my case,
streaming around the house. This method of conversion should work for any DVB
PVR which allows you to export recordings via USB and, of course,
&lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org/">MythTV&lt;/a> or similar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dvb-ripping">DVB Ripping&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have a PlayTV add-on for the PlayStation 3 which enables me to record Freeview
(DVB-T) broadcasts to the PS3 internal hard disk. I mostly use PlayTV to record
films. To prevent the PlayStation 3 hard disk filling up with films I wanted to
export, edit out any adverts and then serve the edited file from my DLNA server
or author it to DVD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This process does not re-encode the audio or video therefore it is fairly quick
and the output is the same quality as the input.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I am using a PlayStation 3 as PVR and MPEG-2 TS (Transport Stream) file
can be converted to a MPEG-2 PS (Program Stream) file using this process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="export-from-playstation-3">Export from PlayStation 3&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="playtv-to-home-menu">PlayTV to Home Menu&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>First we need to move the recording from the PlayTV Library to the PS3 Home Menu.
Start PlayTV, open the Library, select the recording and choose the Move to Home
Menu option.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="copy-from-home-menu-to-external-usb">Copy from Home Menu to External USB&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Quit PlayTV&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Plug in an external (FAT32 formatted) USB drive to the PS3.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to Video on the PS3 Home Menu and select the recording you moved there earlier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Copy from the Options screen and choose the external USB drive as the target.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="clean-mpeg-2-ts-and-convert-to-mpeg-2-ps">Clean MPEG-2 TS and convert to MPEG-2 PS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Plug the USB drive into your Ubuntu workstation and copy the &lt;code>.m2ts&lt;/code> file to your
hard disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will need to &lt;a href="http://project-x.sourceforge.net/">Project X&lt;/a> to clean the
MPEG-2 TS and convert it to MPEG-2 PS.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>apt-get install project-x
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h2 id="edit-out-the-adverts">Edit out the adverts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Start the Project X GUI and load your &lt;code>.m2ts&lt;/code> file.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>File -&amp;gt; Add&lt;/code> and select your .m2ts file.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now use Project X to add cut points to edit out any adverts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="de-multiplex-the-audio-and-video">De-multiplex the audio and video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you have completed your edits you need to &amp;lsquo;demux&amp;rsquo; the &lt;code>.m2ts&lt;/code> file into two
streams, one holding the audio (.mp2) and one holding the video (.m2v).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;code>Prepare &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code> button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>From the &lt;code>Process Window&lt;/code> select the &lt;code>Action&lt;/code> type &lt;code>to M2P&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the start button and wait for the processing to finish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clock the &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Process Windows&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; and quit Project X.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="re-multiplex-the-audio-and-video">Re-multiplex the audio and video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The reason for the de-mux and then re-musing it to ensure the timecodes are
correct, other the video will not playback correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Install MJPEG tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>apt-get install mjpegtools
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Now we need to re-multiplex the audio and video to create a DVD compliant MPEG-2 PS file.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>mplex -f &lt;span style="color:#f60">8&lt;/span> -o muxed-%d.mpg audio.mp2 video.m2v
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The &lt;code>-f 8&lt;/code> option specifies a dvd-compliant stream that is compatible with dvdauthor.
The &lt;code>-o&lt;/code> option specifies the outfile, you can substitute &lt;code>muxed-%d.mpg&lt;/code> with a
more descriptive name if you like. &lt;code>%d&lt;/code> is expanded to a number if &lt;code>mplex&lt;/code> decides
to split the output to several files, this usually happens when the recording
contains commercials and is nothing to worry about.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="author-dvd">Author DVD&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The MPEG-2 PS file that has been created should be suitable for DVD authoring
using DeVeDe. When adding MPEG-2 PS files created using the method above open
the DeVeDe &lt;code>Advanced options&lt;/code> and select &lt;em>This file is already a DVD/xCD-suitable
MPEG-PS file&lt;/em> in the &lt;code>Misc&lt;/code> menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="references">References&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://project-x.sourceforge.net/">http://project-x.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://ttcut.tritime.de/index.2.html">http://ttcut.tritime.de/index.2.html&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://gopchop.org/index.php">http://gopchop.org/index.php&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://gopchop.sourceforge.net/">http://gopchop.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.rastersoft.com/programas/devede.html">http://www.rastersoft.com/programas/devede.html&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Export PlayTV recorded video from PlayStation 3</summary></item><item><title>DVD Box Sets - Extended Film Watching Session is Coming</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-box-sets-extended-film-watching-session-is-coming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2006 12:25:47 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-box-sets-extended-film-watching-session-is-coming/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I finally got around to ordering some stuff from Amazon.co.uk using the
vouchers I was given as present at Christmas. I have ordered The Matrix
Trilogy and The Lord of the Rings Trilogy (Extended Edition Box Set) which I
hope arrive before the weekend as my wife is away for a few days which should be
enough time to get through both box sets 😄&lt;/p></description><summary>Planning some DVD binge viewing</summary></item></channel></rss>