<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Messaging on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/messaging/</link><description>Recent content in Messaging on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 19:38:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/messaging/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android Gmail Conversation View</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/android-gmail-conversation-view/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 19:38:34 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/android-gmail-conversation-view/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently migrated several domains I manage for family and friends
to the &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> version of &lt;a href="http://http://www.google.com/enterprise/apps/business/">Google Apps&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I setup the Gmail app on their Android phones for them and email
arrives promptly and spam is pretty much eradicated. Happy days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, the Gmail app for Android only supports a conversation view of
emails. My wife and I hate that and have actually missed emails because
new emails get burried in an earlier email conversation way down your
inbox. Frustratingly changing the preferences on the Gmail website to
disable the conversation view does not propagate to the Gmail app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The best solution to this that I have found is to to not use the Gmail
app and install &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fsck.k9">K-9 Mail&lt;/a>
instead connected to Google App accounts via IMAP and SMTP. K-9 Mail
(only?) supports a traditional list view of your emails and unlike the
built in Email app for Android K9-Mail supports push notifications so
you get near instantaneous notification of new email.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to support the K-9 Mail developer then consider purchasing
&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kaitenmail">Kaiten Mail&lt;/a>
which is an enhanced version of K-9 Mail and is particularly good on Android
tablets.&lt;/p></description><summary>List view email clients for Android that support Gmail</summary></item><item><title>Zindus contact sync for Thunderbird and Zimbra</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/zindus-contact-sync-for-thunderbird-and-zimbra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 15:41:24 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/zindus-contact-sync-for-thunderbird-and-zimbra/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I setup the mail server at work I picked &lt;a href="http://www.zimbra.com/">Zimbra&lt;/a>.
It&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today Zimbra just got a bit better when I found &lt;a href="http://www.zindus.com">Zindus&lt;/a>.
Zindus is open source software and runs on all Thunderbird platforms including
Windows, Mac OSX and Linux. Zindus can sync your contacts between Zimbra and
Thunderbird. It syncs everything from Address Books to your GAL (Global Address List).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It currently supports ZCS 3.x to 5.x. Adding the &lt;a href="http://www.mozilla.org/projects/calendar/">Lightning&lt;/a>
and Zindus add-ons to Thunderbird create a very complete desktop client to
Zimbra for any platform. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to share to good news with my Outlook users.&lt;/p></description><summary>Zimbra contact syncing for Thunderbird on Linux</summary></item></channel></rss>