<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DLNA on Wimpy's World</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/tags/dlna/</link><description>Recent content in DLNA on Wimpy's World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</managingEditor><webMaster>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 21:49:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wimpysworld.com/tags/dlna/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up MiniDLNA on Open Media Vault</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/setting-up-minidlna-on-open-media-vault/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 21:49:09 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/setting-up-minidlna-on-open-media-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have &lt;a href="http://www.openmediavault.org/">Open Media Vault&lt;/a> running on a
&lt;a href="http://www8.hp.com/uk/en/products/proliant-servers/product-detail.html?oid=5336624">HP ProLiant MicroServer G7 N54L&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OpenMediaVault (OMV) is a network attached storage (NAS) solution based on
&lt;a href="http://www.debian.org">Debian&lt;/a> Linux. At the time of writing OMV 0.5.x is
based on Debian 6.0 (Squeeze).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In recent months &lt;a href="http://www.plexapp.com">Plex&lt;/a> has taken over just about all
media streaming duties in our house, with the expectation of streaming music
because Plex music playback and streaming is seriously lacking (no playlists!).
So, &lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/minidlna/">MiniDLNA&lt;/a> is still required for
serving up music around the house.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="install-minidlna-on-omv">Install MiniDLNA on OMV&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>There is a 3rd party plugin repository for Open Media Vault which includes
packages to install MiniDLNA and a WebUI plugin for managing MiniDLNA via OMV.
I upgraded to OMV 0.5.x this morning. and with the 0.5.x the Plugin API changed
and as of the time of writing none of the 3rd party plugins had not been migrated
to OMV 0.5.x. That said, MiniDLNA is super simple to configure so a WebUI is
not a requirement for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MiniDLNA is not currently packaged for Debian Squeeze in the official repositories but
&lt;a href="http://blog.steve.org.uk/minidlna_is_now_packaged.html">Steve Kemp&lt;/a> has packaged
a fairly up-to-date version of MiniDLNA for Squeeze. Brilliant! Do the following as
&lt;code>root&lt;/code> to install MiniDLNA.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>wget http://packages.steve.org.uk/minidlna/apt-key.pub
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>apt-key add apt-key.pub
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>echo deb http://packages.steve.org.uk/minidlna/squeeze/ ./&lt;span style="color:#87ceeb">&amp;#34; &amp;gt; /etc/apt/sources.list.d/minidlna.list
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#87ceeb">echo &amp;#34;&lt;/span>deb-src http://packages.steve.org.uk/minidlna/squeeze/ ./&lt;span style="color:#87ceeb">&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/apt/sources.list.d/minidlna.list
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve done that run the following.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>apt-get update
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>apt-get install minidlna
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The MiniDLNA defaults in Steve&amp;rsquo;s package assume you have your music in
&lt;code>/srv/music&lt;/code>. So you&amp;rsquo;ll probably need to modify &lt;code>/etc/minidlna/minidlna.conf&lt;/code>
accordingly. From this point &lt;code>man minidlna&lt;/code> and &lt;code>man minidlna.conf&lt;/code> will
guide you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="references">References&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://blog.steve.org.uk/minidlna_is_now_packaged.html">http://blog.steve.org.uk/minidlna_is_now_packaged.html&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://packages.steve.org.uk/minidlna/">http://packages.steve.org.uk/minidlna/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/minidlna/">http://sourceforge.net/projects/minidlna/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Music streaming with MiniDLNA on Open Media Vault</summary></item><item><title>Mediatomb vs. MiniDLNA</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mediatomb-vs-minidlna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 15:34:12 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mediatomb-vs-minidlna/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href="http://mediatomb.cc/">Mediatomb&lt;/a> for nearly two years now but
decided to give &lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/minidlna/">MiniDLNA&lt;/a> a whirl
since it is a fully fledged DLNA server whereas Mediatomb is UPnP only. I&amp;rsquo;m
currently running both Mediatomb SVN and MiniDLNA CVS. So, how does MiniDLNA
compare to Mediatomb?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>MiniDLNA is easier to compile, configure, uses less RAM and has less software
dependencies than Mediatomb.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MiniDLNA doesn&amp;rsquo;t currently support music play lists or Last.fm scrobbling.
Mediatomb supports &lt;code>.m3u&lt;/code> and &lt;code>.pls&lt;/code> playlists but requires a 3rd party patch
to add Last.fm scrobbling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MiniDLNA doesn&amp;rsquo;t support dynamic video thumbnail creation, which would be
nice to have but is not essential, cover images are supported. Mediatomb
supports video thumbnails via &lt;code>ffmpegthumbnailer&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MiniDLNA doesn&amp;rsquo;t currently have any transcoding support. This is of little
consequence for me since I import video content into my library in a format
natively supported by the PS3, either MP3, MPEG-2 TS or MPEG-4. Mediatomb
does support transcoding but it is somewhat fiddly to setup and you can&amp;rsquo;t
pause transcoded content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MiniDLNA works &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;out of the box&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> with the PS3 (and other DLNA clients)
while Mediatomb requires some tweaking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mediatomb&amp;rsquo;s default video import script doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit how I organise my
video library, but MiniDLNA suits my video library perfectly.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>So, as of today I am running both Mediatomb and MiniDLNA. Mediatomb is
exclusively handling audio since playlist and Last.fm support are essential
for me. MiniDLNA is now handling video exclusively. I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with the
results but should MiniDLNA add .m3u/.pls play lists and Last.fm support I
will switch everything to MiniDLNA.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-years-later">2 years later&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since writing this post MiniDLNA added support for playlists. It still doesn&amp;rsquo;t
support Last.fm scrobbling though. Despite that I switched to MiniDLNA and it
has been streaming audio and video around the house for that last couple of
years.&lt;/p></description><summary>Comparing Mediatomb and MiniDLNA streaming servers</summary></item><item><title>DVD to MPEG2-TS Ripper for Linux</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ts-ripper-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 07:53:58 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ts-ripper-for-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>A while back I released a script that rips a DVD to MPEG-2 PS allowing the
user to select one audio stream and one subtitle stream. Optionally the video
can be requantised, using M2VRequantiser and an ISO image created. If creating
an ISO image the chapters are also preserved from the original DVD. You can
see the original post below.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="2009-04-dvd-mpeg2ps-ripper-linux.html">DVD to MPEG-2 PS Ripper for Linux&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve just released an update to that original script which fixes subtitles in
the original MPEG-2 PS mode but now adds the capability to rip MPEG-2 TS. The
video stream can still be shrunk and in MPEG-2 PS mode the video is still
requantised but in MPEG-2 TS mode the video is re-encoded as H.264.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Requantising is faster but can introduce artifacting. H.264 encoding is
slower, but produces very good quality. I am currently re-importing my entire
DVD collection, using this script, to my DLNA server using MPEG-2 TS and
re-encoding the video to H.264. This gives me high quality rips at relatively
small size (~3Gb) whilst preserving Dolby Digital 5.1 audio. Perfect for
playback via DLNA on the PS3. Some things to be aware of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Subtitles are only supported in MPEG-2 PS mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MPEG-2 PS files created by this script are DVD compliant.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ISO files created by this script will preserve the chapters from the original DVD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The PS3 can only play DTS audio in MPEG-2 PS streams when they have been authored to DVD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The PS3 can only play subtitles in MPEG-2 PS streams when they have been authored to DVD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The PS3 can&amp;rsquo;t play DTS audio in MPEG-2 TS streams therefore this script will transcode DTS to AC3 when in MPEG-2 TS mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To download the script and find out how to make full use of it visit the
release page below.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/DVD-to-MPG">DVD-to-MPG&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Ripping DVDs to MPEG-2 Transport Streams for DLNA streaming</summary></item><item><title>DVD to MPEG2-PS Ripper for Linux</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ps-ripper-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 16:50:31 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/dvd-to-mpeg2-ps-ripper-for-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every so often I find myself in looking through the ex-rental DVD &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;bargain
bin&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>. Quite often I find something I consider a bargain. However, the
experience of watching an ex-rental DVD is typically ruined by the various
trailers and marketing guff at the start which you can&amp;rsquo;t skip. My wife hates
that stuff, and I love my wife, so I routinely rip the main feature of newly
acquired ex-rental DVD movies so we can avoid that crap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I run a Mediatomb DLNA server and I want to load it with all my DVDs. Ripping
them helps reduce the amount of storage I require. MPEG2-PS files are
compatible with my PlayStation 3 which is the client to my Mediatomb DLNA server.
As a solution to the above I created a script, which can extract the main feature
from a DVD video, allowing the user to select one audio stream and one subtitle
stream. Optionally the video can be requantised, using M2VRequantiser, and an ISO
image created. If creating an ISO image the chapters are also preserved from
the original DVD. I&amp;rsquo;ve lobbed my code into GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/DVD-to-MPG">DVD-to-MPG&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Ripping DVDs to MPEG2-PS for streaming via UPnP</summary></item><item><title>Converting Matroska to M2TS for PS3 and Mediatomb</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/converting-matroska-to-m2ts-for-ps3-and-mediatomb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 16:19:24 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/converting-matroska-to-m2ts-for-ps3-and-mediatomb/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been a while since I last posted, mainly due to not having Internet
access at home for a month. Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m online again and I have been tinkering
with various projects the most recent of which is Matroska conversion (again).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="matroska-to-mp4">Matroska to MP4&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For sometime I have been converting Martoska files to MPEG-4 with AAC 5.1 audio
so I can stream them via Mediatomb to my PlayStation 3. The conversion process
works well although there is some overhead in transcoding the audio and the
AAC 5.1 audio is not as good quality as the original AC3 or DTS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested I&amp;rsquo;ve put my code in GitHub, the script automates the
whole process.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/MKV-to-MP4">MPV-to-MP4&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="matroska-to-m2ts">Matroska to M2TS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A little while back I read it was possible to convert those same Matroska file
to M2TS files which, so long as the audio is AC3, so takes much less time to
convert. As the PlayStation 3 can&amp;rsquo;t play DTS audio streams inside a M2TS container
there is still a requirement to transcode DTS to AC3. That said the conversion to
M2TS requires less file I/O than converting to MPEG-4 and is therefore it is
generally a quicker conversion method, typically just 2 or 3 minutes on my
workstation at home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus the audio quality of the AC3 or transcoded DTS is better than that of
transcoded AAC 5.1. I&amp;rsquo;ve created my own script to fully automate the conversion
process. The script has been tested on Ubuntu 8.10 64-bit but there is an
outside chance it will work on Mac OS X if you can get the required tools
installed. Again, you can find my script on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/flexiondotorg/MKV-to-M2TS">MPV-to-M2TS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><summary>Fast conversion of Matroska video to MPEG2-TS</summary></item><item><title>Mediatomb 0.12 - Streaming audio and video around the house</title><link>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mediatomb-0.12-streaming-audio-and-video-around-the-house/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 16:23:39 +0000</pubDate><author>martin@wimpress.com (Martin Wimpress)</author><guid>https://wimpysworld.com/posts/mediatomb-0.12-streaming-audio-and-video-around-the-house/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://mediatomb.cc/">Mediatomb&lt;/a> is an open source (GPL) UPnP MediaServer
with a nice web user interface, it allows you to stream your digital media
through your home network and listen to/watch it on a variety of UPnP
compatible devices, such as the PlayStation in my case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mediatomb 0.12 is not yet released as final yet but it is certainly stable
enough for general use, so I spent the last week migrating from Mediatomb 0.11
to Mediatomb 0.12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently finished ripping my entire CD collection (344 CDs) to MP3 and I
am currently ripping my DVD collection (85 done so far) to MP4 with AAC 5.1
audio. The &amp;lsquo;Music&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Video&amp;rsquo; folders in our home directories are mounted via
NFS. The Mediatomb server uses the same data sources so any playlists or new
music/videos we might import are immediately reflected in Mediatomb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our entire CD library is now available at the click of a button, automatically
organised by genre, artist and date. We have also created some playlists
in &lt;code>.m3u&lt;/code> or &lt;code>.pls&lt;/code> format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New to Mediatomb 0.12 is the ability to scrobble your music to
&lt;a href="http://www.last.fm">Last.fm&lt;/a>, this a killer feature for me and why I chose to
migrate to 0.12 before it goes final.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ripped the CDs using &lt;a href="http://www.burtonini.com/blog/computers/sound-juicer">SoundJuicer&lt;/a>,
since I can configure it to use &lt;a href="http://lame.cvs.sourceforge.net/viewvc/lame/lame/doc/html/presets.html">LAME presets&lt;/a>.
I then used the &lt;a href="http://musicbrainz.org/doc/PicardTagger">Music Brainz Picard Tagger&lt;/a> to
add additional tagging and embed cover art and then applied ReplayGain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally my wife and I use &lt;a href="http://banshee-project.org/">Banshee&lt;/a> to manage the
music library on our computers, including the creation of playlists and syncing
to our iPods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am using &lt;a href="http://handbrake.fr/">Handbrake&lt;/a> to rip the DVDs to MP4. I&amp;rsquo;ve created a
new PS3 compatible profile which is focused on quality, I&amp;rsquo;ll post details
about that in the future. Mediatomb 0.12 has some experimental features to
stream video content from .ISO images of DVDs. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to play with that but
it sounds very cool. I&amp;rsquo;ve also created a script which queries IMDB to
categorise our film library by genre and create summary information about
each film in the library. I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting more about that soon. I haven&amp;rsquo;t
finalised how we will integrate Photo management with Mediatomb yet, but that
is that final piece in the puzzle.&lt;/p></description><summary>In home streaming via UPnP with Mediatomb</summary></item></channel></rss>